<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Jon Shafer (Firaxis Games) -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_AGREE_SHORT_1">
			<Text>Very well.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_AGREE_SHORT_2">
			<Text>All right.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_AGREE_SHORT_3">
			<Text>Certainly.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_AGREE_SHORT_4">
			<Text>It is agreed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_AGREE_SHORT_5">
			<Text>Oh, very well.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_AGREE_SHORT_6">
			<Text>I suppose I must.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_AGREE_SHORT_7">
			<Text>Excellent.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_ATTACKED_1">
			<Text>Very well - on your head be it!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_ATTACKED_3">
			<Text>You dare! You will suffer for your monstrous arrogance!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DECLAREWAR_1">
			<Text>Your many insults to Us and to Our loyal subjects will not go unpunished - prepare for war!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DECLAREWAR_2">
			<Text>By the grace of God, your days are numbered. Prepare for war!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DECLAREWAR_3">
			<Text>The time for polite speeches and pretty gestures has ended - we shall meet on the field of battle!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>You have bested us on the field of battle. We congratulate you in your victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>You have defeated us, for now. But England shall rise again one day, even mightier than before!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>You have triumphed over us. The day is yours.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DEMANDTRIBUTE_ANGRY">
			<Text>Give us what we want or suffer the consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DEMANDTRIBUTE_HAPPY">
			<Text>My beloved friend, can you assist Us in Our hour of need?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DEMANDTRIBUTE_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>England has needs - needs that only you can fulfill. We trust that you will rise to the occasion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DISAGREE_SHORT_1">
			<Text>No.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DISAGREE_SHORT_2">
			<Text>Certainly not.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DISAGREE_SHORT_3">
			<Text>We decline.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DISAGREE_SHORT_4">
			<Text>Of course not.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DISAGREE_SHORT_5">
			<Text>That's unacceptable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DISAGREE_SHORT_6">
			<Text>You cannot be serious!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DISAGREE_SHORT_7">
			<Text>I beg your pardon?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Greetings. We hope that our two people meet as friends, rather than foes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>You are well met. I pray that it was an auspicious wind that brought us together.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>We are pleased to meet you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_FIRSTGREETING_4">
			<Text>Welcome to England.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GOODBYE_1">
			<Text>Good day.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GOODBYE_2">
			<Text>Farewell.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GOODBYE_3">
			<Text>Goodbye.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GOODBYE_4">
			<Text>Until we meet again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GOODBYE_5">
			<Text>Go away now.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GOODBYE_6">
			<Text>That is all.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GOODBYE_7">
			<Text>Away with you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GREETING_1">
			<Text>Well met!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GREETING_2">
			<Text>Hello again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GREETING_3">
			<Text>Greetings.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GREETING_4">
			<Text>Welcome.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GREETING_5">
			<Text>Oh, it's you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GREETING_6">
			<Text>Well?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_GREETING_7">
			<Text>What do you want?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_LETSHEARIT_1">
			<Text>Let's hear it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_LETSHEARIT_2">
			<Text>Go ahead.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_LETSHEARIT_3">
			<Text>Proceed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_LETSHEARIT_4">
			<Text>I'm listening.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_LETSHEARIT_5">
			<Text>Yes?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_LETSHEARIT_6">
			<Text>You were saying?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_LETSHEARIT_7">
			<Text>And?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_LETSHEARIT_8">
			<Text>Go on.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_LOSEWAR_1">
			<Text>Well then, that's settled. I can only hope that our relations remain peaceful and friendly in the future.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>My loving people, we have been persuaded by some, that are careful of our safety, to take heed how we commit ourselves to armed multitudes, for fear of treachery; but I assure you, I do not desire to live to distrust my faithful and loving people. Let tyrants fear; I have always so behaved myself that, under God, I have placed my chiefest strength and safeguard in the loyal hearts and good will of my subjects. And therefore I am come amongst you at this time, not as for my recreation or sport, but being resolved, in the midst and heat of the battle, to live or die amongst you all; to lay down, for my God, and for my kingdom, and for my people, my honor and my blood, even the dust. I know I have but the body of a weak and feeble woman; but I have the heart of a king, and of a king of England, too; and think foul scorn that Parma or Spain, or any prince of Europe, should dare to invade the borders of my realms: to which, rather than any dishonor should grow by me, I myself will take up arms; I myself will be your general, judge, and rewarder of every one of your virtues in the field. I know already, by your forwardness, that you have deserved rewards and crowns; and we do assure you, on the word of a prince, they shall be duly paid you. In the mean my lieutenant general shall be in my stead, than whom never prince commanded a more noble and worthy subject; not doubting by your obedience to my general, by your concord in the camp, and by your valor in the field, we shall shortly have a famous victory over the enemies of my God, of my kingdom, and of my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_QUOTE_2">
			<Text>My loving people … I am come amongst you at this time, not as for my recreation or sport, but being resolved, in the midst and heat of the battle, to live or die amongst you all; to lay down, for my God, and for my kingdom, and for my people, my honor and my blood, even the dust. I know I have but the body of a weak and feeble woman; but I have the heart of a king, and of a king of England, too; and think foul scorn that Parma or Spain, or any prince of Europe, should dare to invade the borders of my realms: to which, rather than any dishonor should grow by me, I myself will take up arms … not doubting by your obedience to my general, by your concord in the camp, and by your valor in the field, we shall shortly have a famous victory over the enemies of my God, of my kingdom, and of my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_ANGRY_1">
			<Text>England is not so generous. You must do better than that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_ANGRY_2">
			<Text>That's not good enough.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_ANGRY_3">
			<Text>You must do better than that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_ANGRY_4">
			<Text>Almost…</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_1">
			<Text>Come now! England can ill-afford to be so generous, even to dear friends! Will you not improve your offer?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_2">
			<Text>Is that the best you can do?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_3">
			<Text>You're almost there…</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_4">
			<Text>Almost…</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_NEUTRAL_1">
			<Text>Come now! Such penuriousness ill-becomes a leader of your stature! Surely you can improve your paltry offer!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_NEUTRAL_2">
			<Text>Can you do better?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_NEUTRAL_3">
			<Text>That's not quite good enough.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_NEUTRAL_4">
			<Text>Almost…</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NO_ANGRY">
			<Text>Your request is an insult to England. We refuse.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NO_HAPPY">
			<Text>My dear friend,  whilst We would personally give you everything we possess, unto our very last farthing, Our advisors are somewhat less generous. I therefore must regretfully decline your offer.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NO_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>We implore you not to waste Our time with such foolishness.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_YES_ANGRY">
			<Text>Oh very well. I suppose I must. We are agreed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_YES_HAPPY">
			<Text>We congratulate you on your bargaining skill and acumen! We accept your offer.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_YES_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>Your offer is agreeable to Us. We accept.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADEREQUEST_ANGRY">
			<Text>Here is Our offer - and it is far better than you deserve.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADEREQUEST_HAPPY">
			<Text>My dear friend, would you be interested in a trade agreement with England?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADEREQUEST_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>Commercial intercourse is the lifeblood of civilization, don't you agree?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRIBUTE_NO_ANGRY">
			<Text>You presume to demand tribute from Us? Go away, you hateful villain!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRIBUTE_NO_HAPPY">
			<Text>Friends should not treat each other thusly. We are surprised at your temerity!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRIBUTE_NO_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>How amusing you are. Certainly not.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRIBUTE_YES_ANGRY">
			<Text>You have Us at a disadvantage now, but it may not always be so. We shall remember this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRIBUTE_YES_HAPPY">
			<Text>It is Our pleasure to assist Our friend and ally in their hour of need.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRIBUTE_YES_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>Oh, very well, I suppose we have no choice.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_WARBLUFF_1">
			<Text>How disappointing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_WARBLUFF_2">
			<Text>How very disappointing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_WARBLUFF_3">
			<Text>Indeed? I trust that you will not live to regret your short-sightedness.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_WARBLUFF_4">
			<Text>How foolish of you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_WARBLUFF_5">
			<Text>Your foolish pride will be the death of you if you do not take care.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_WARBLUFF_6">
			<Text>Very well. On your head be it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_WINWAR_1">
			<Text>England shall always rise triumphant over her foes! You would do well to remember that in the future.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>
