<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Sid Meier's Civilization V -->
<!--Copyright Firaxis Games 2010 -->
<!--File created by Paul Murphy-->
<GameData>
  <Language_en_US>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_CONQUEST_TITLE">
      <Text>Conquest Victory</Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_CONQUEST_TEXT">
      <Text>
        You have triumphed through Conquest, defeating all of your enemies upon the field of battle! You have scattered their armies and captured their cities! Long will the people remember your glorious victory!
      </Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_ALTCONQUEST_TITLE">
      <Text>Alternate Conquest Victory</Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_ALTCONQUEST_TEXT">
      <Text>
        The world has been convulsed by war. Many great and powerful civilizations have fallen, but you have survived - and emerged victorious! The world will long remember your glorious triumph!
      </Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_SCIENCE_TITLE">
      <Text>Science Victory</Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_SCIENCE_TEXT">
      <Text>
        You have achieved victory through mastery of Science! You have conquered the mysteries of nature and led your people on a voyage to a brave new world! Your triumph will be remembered as long as the stars burn in the night sky!
      </Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_DIPLOMATIC_TITLE">
      <Text>Diplomatic Victory</Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_DIPLOMATIC_TEXT">
      <Text>
        You have triumphed over your foes through the art of Diplomacy! Your cunning and wisdom have earned you great friends - and divided and sown confusion among your enemies! Forever will you be remembered as the leader who brought peace to a weary world!
      </Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_CULTURE_TITLE">
      <Text>Culture Victory</Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_CULTURE_TEXT">
      <Text>
        You have achieved victory through the awesome power of your Culture. Your civilization's greatness - the magnificence of its monuments and the power of its artists - have astounded the world! Poets will honor you for as long as beauty brings gladness to a weary heart.
      </Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_LOSS_TITLE">
      <Text>Loss</Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_LOSS_TEXT">
      <Text>
        You have been defeated. Your civilization has been overwhelmed by its many foes. But your people do not despair, for they know that one day you shall return - and lead them forward to victory!
      </Text>
    </Row>

	<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EXTENDED_GAME_YES">
		<Text>Wait! Just... one... more... turn...</Text>
	</Row>
	
	<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_EXTENDED_GAME_DEMO">
		<Text>BUY THE FULL VERSION</Text>
	</Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_DEMO_TEXT">
      <Text>
        Your great and powerful civilization is well on its way, but your time here has come to an end. Your people do not despair, for they know that one day you shall return and lead them forward to victory!
      </Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_VICTORY_DEMO_BULLET_TEXT">
      <Text>
        [ICON_BULLET]Experience the full Civilization V experience with the full game.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Lead 18 civilizations from the dawn of man to the space age.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Download exclusive content and mods, and compete with gamers worldwide.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]What will your civilization stand for?
      </Text>
    </Row>

    <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GO_BEYOND_EARTH">
      <Text>GO BEYOND EARTH</Text>
    </Row>
  </Language_en_US>
</GameData>